<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>The Suck Zone</title>
 <link href="http://ww1x.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ww1x.com/"/>
 <updated>2012-07-02T17:11:58-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://ww1x.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Rockwell Schrock</name>
   <email>schrockwell@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>SOTA Activation of Mount Toby</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/sota/2012/07/01/mount-toby.html"/>
   <updated>2012-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/W_pDKFd7KZg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Hot day, lots of signal fading, but nice view and got 10 QSOs on 20m&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DX:&lt;/strong&gt; Serbia&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S.:&lt;/strong&gt; AR, IN, MA, NC, GA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jess and I tackled one of the larger peaks in the area, Mount Toby. Temperatures were in the low 90s as we hit the trail. From the trailhead on Reservation Road, we took the Robert Frost Trail out, then followed the power line trail straight up the side of the mountain. And by straight up, we mean straight up. The last half mile had about 400 feet of elevation gain. It was strenuous, but a good workout was had by all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;margin: 0 0 2em 2em&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/US-7DSvtQEIraYddDdK9edMTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=directlink&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-uXM_dBpA2p0/T_INAdHA13I/AAAAAAAADt4/bkjoV6TQhOk/s400/IMG_1503.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summit is circled by trees, but the nine-story fire tower (turned antenna farm) offers a stiff breeze and a full 360 degree view of the valley and surrounding peaks. There were a number of picnic tables, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had trouble making it out on 20m today. Nearly all stations who were not local were reporting fading on my signal, which makes me suspicious that something might have been wrong with the rig or antenna setup. Maybe I put it too close to the guy wires for the fire tower? I wasn&amp;#8217;t able to achieve a good &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SWR&lt;/span&gt; as I normally do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked a lot of the regular &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; chasers like AJ5C, WA2USA, as well as the local &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; guys. I even worked a husband/wife pair back-to-back with consecutive callsigns: KB1RJC and KB1RJD! Pretty cool. I was also able to land YT1A (Serbia!) and N4PN who were working the Canada Day contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N1FJ also took the time to work me on CW, which was a treat. I&amp;#8217;m not very fast at CW yet, so I did not copy most of what he sent, but I was able to review it in the video later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to some other hikers at the summit and determined the best way down was Tower Road, a dirt access road that was a big longer in distance, but much less steep. It made for a pleasant trek down, which was good because some storm cells were in the area. Luckily, the weather stayed to our south, and we had sunny skies the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>VHF QSO Party 2012</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/2012/06/11/vhf-qso-party.html"/>
   <updated>2012-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;margin: 0 0 2em 2em&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/6DDUitm0Hfg2EXWuGtTictMTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=directlink&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-kLKWgEY6q30/T-_bdh5yuhI/AAAAAAAADtU/B430s8eRfpo/s400/photo%25202.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having only recently acquired a radio that supports 50 MHz, I didn&amp;#8217;t have a lot of experience on the lowest &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VHF&lt;/span&gt; band until now. In preparation, I constructed a modification to the homebrew Buddipole that converts it into a 3-element Yagi (plans forthcoming). All elements are Buddipole &amp;#8220;Featherweight&amp;#8221; telescopic whips that are lightweight, portable, and adjustable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday afternoon I drove to my perennial radio spot: Mount Sugarloaf in Sunderland, Massachusetts. The state reservation boasts a 400 foot elevation gain over the surrounding area, with sheer cliffs and a great observation deck overlooking the Connecticut River valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, it has a clear view of the west, south, and east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday afternoon was fun. I operated from the mountain from the beginning of the contest, 1800Z, until to 2230Z (2 to 6:30 PM local time). Most contacts were local, but a number of Florida stations soon came through! I packed it up with 53 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/span&gt; QSOs under my belt, most of them 100W. I also pulled out the 2m tape measure Yagi and had some fun with local contacts on FM and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left;margin: 2em 2em 2em 0&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/Tzkeo0G6d6ADzKOvPk3oiNMTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=directlink&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-DJxRHuIPsik/T-_bd2t811I/AAAAAAAADtc/zbMOUAI2Zu8/s400/photo%25203.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hopped on again Sunday afternoon around 2100Z, this time portable on the lawn outside my apartment. The band was dead, dead, dead. I had a nice ragchew with Thomas, KA1MDA, to pass the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, things started happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Thomas worked MW0ZZK in Wales and pointed me to his frequency. Just like that, I got my first DX &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VHF&lt;/span&gt; contact. Next was W0OGH in Arizona. Suddenly Canada, Alabama, Nevada, and Montana all started rolling in. I continued to knock out QSOs until the sun went down and my battery was finally drained, which was around 0115Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was amazing to hear different &amp;#8220;hot spots&amp;#8221; come in from around the country. Sometimes the signal fading was so severe at times that a station would disappear in the time it took me to send my callsign. Such is the nature of the Magic Band, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, I made 104 QSOs in 50 grid squares for a total of 5200 points. 14 of those contacts were on 2m (2 FM), and the rest were 6m &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/span&gt; at 100W.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VHF&lt;/span&gt; antennas being so small, this was a fun contest to operate portable. The 6m beam really proved its worth, and I was surprised to get 4.5 hours out of the battery running 100W the entire time. I probably could have gotten by with lower power, but at least now I have a good benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SOTA Activation of Mount Tom</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/sota/2012/05/20/mount-tom.html"/>
   <updated>2012-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/8N4Il78r2tw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; A long, hot hike, and a so-so 20m band, but all the more rewarding&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DX:&lt;/strong&gt; Scotland, Wales, France, Czech Republic&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S.:&lt;/strong&gt; MA, AR, OR, NC, NY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hike was a little more than we had bargained for. We got a late start and had to fight the sun and heat for this 2.5 mile hike out the summit that ran along the edge of the ridge, not offering much in the way of shade or places to take a break. However, the view of the valley was breathtaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 10 QSOs in just 25 minutes, we hoofed it back to the car just in time to make it out of the park before they locked up the gates for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The homebrew Buddipole performed well on 20m, as usual, and I ran 25 watts into it this time. I was lucky that I did not experience too much interference from the myriad of broadcast antennas atop the summit.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A 20 Meter Kite Antenna</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/2012/05/12/kite-antenna.html"/>
   <updated>2012-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/UsJ2Copypuw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always wanted to try a wire antenna suspended by a kite. Conditions were ripe on this blustery spring afternoon to take the kite out for a fly on Quabbin Hill, site of my most recent &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s all in the video, but this was what I consider a rousing success. Here&amp;#8217;s what I would have done differently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Get a bigger kite with more lift and possibly a higher flying angle&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use smaller-gauge stranded wire, which is lighter and easier for the kite to lift&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Pick a day with steadier (less gusty) wind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SOTA Activation of Quabbin Hill</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/sota/2012/04/20/quabbin-hill.html"/>
   <updated>2012-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; A windy day in which 20m opened into Eastern Europe&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DX:&lt;/strong&gt; Spain, England, Italy, Slovenia, Croatia&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S.:&lt;/strong&gt; MA, AR, OR, NC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No video today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activation was a spur-of-the-moment idea. With rain impeding on our weekend plans, Jess and I decided to take a quick jaunt up Quabbin Hill on this Friday afternoon. The hill is a great recreational area that overlooks the Quabbin Reservoir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked 20m for an hour, racking up QSOs with the usual &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; chasers. I even made contact with N4EX, who was very nearly buried in the noise. I was able to pull out his callsign and complete the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;QSO&lt;/span&gt;, but man, it took a while. I could barely even hear him, and the wind didn&amp;#8217;t help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 20:00 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UTC&lt;/span&gt;, the band appeared to suddenly open up into eastern Europe. I heard many Italy stations, and one even responded to my CQ! I was still running just 5 watts at this point! I then knocked out QSOs into Slovenia, and at 25 watts I was able to reach Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I really love about amateur radio: I can talk down the street in one breath, then talk across the world in the next. The unpredictability keeps me coming back for more, because you never know the next station who will come back to your CQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/efZUiiAsYJGannbpWLumS9MTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=directlink&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-9C2Wgac4ehw/T5JN7uwCg0I/AAAAAAAADpM/2T7XzQZdT1M/s640/IMG_1318%2520copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SOTA Activation of Mount Norwottock</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/sota/2012/04/14/mount-norwottuck.html"/>
   <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/MAXayivKYe0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Had good results on 20m and 17m today, including a summit-to-summit with Germany, and a station in Oman&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DX:&lt;/strong&gt; Germany, Oman&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S.:&lt;/strong&gt; MA, AR, WI, AL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ross and Jess joined me for this weekend&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; expedition in the Holyoke Range. This was the first portable deployment of my homemade Buddipole antenna system, and it was quite effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to talk to many members of the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; Jerks for the first time, which was great. I started on 20m and shifted up to 17m to get away from the main bands a little bit. This opened up the door for a few more QSOs, including a summit-to-summit with German station &lt;a href=&quot;http://qrz.com/db/dl3sba&quot;&gt;DL3SBA&lt;/a&gt; on the peak &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sotawatch.org/summits.php?summit=DM/NW-135&quot;&gt;DM/NW-135&lt;/a&gt;. I had tried to work him on 20m earlier with no success, so I&amp;#8217;m glad he was able to find me when I switched bands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another big contact, albeit on 100W, was with &lt;a href=&quot;http://qrz.com/db/a41mx&quot;&gt;A41MX&lt;/a&gt; in Oman. I was tuned to an open frequency on 17m, chatting with another ham who happened to be hiking, when this signal popped up out of nowhere. I&amp;#8217;m glad I snagged him before the pileup began.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SOTA Activation of Pine Mountain</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/sota/2012/03/24/pine-mountain.html"/>
   <updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/cWIZEjPbfR0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/span&gt; contest made QSOs tough, but squeezed out 4 QSOs for an activation point&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DX:&lt;/strong&gt; Canada, Scotland&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S.:&lt;/strong&gt; AR, ID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jess and I took to the hills for the second weekend in a row, this time near her home in southwestern Connecticut. Pine Mountain was an easy hike, but the peak was a little tricky to find because the trail did not lead directly to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;WPX&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/span&gt; contest was going on this weekend, so the bands were jam-packed. Despite this, the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; chasers were resilient and came through to give me enough contacts for a successful activation. Thanks, guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first portable deployment of the Dummipole dipole system featured in the video. It is fully configurable to any band&amp;#8212;-just cut the wire to length! No balun here. It functioned brilliantly on 15m tied to some trees at breast-height, and scored me a contact in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First SOTA Activation on Bare Mountain</title>
   <link href="http://ww1x.com/sota/2012/03/19/bare-mountain.html"/>
   <updated>2012-03-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://ww1x.com{ post.id }}</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ThNJOdhKpxk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; 13 QSOs on 20m in tough band conditions, but a great day to be outside and work &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DX:&lt;/strong&gt; Spain, England, Italy, Austria, German&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S.:&lt;/strong&gt; WI, MI, OR, AR, FL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; Madness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One video was all it took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can thank my obsession with Summits On The Air on one &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qrz.com/db/WG0AT&quot;&gt;Steve Galchutt, WG0AT&lt;/a&gt;, also known as &amp;#8220;the goat man&amp;#8221;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/user/goathiker/&quot;&gt;His YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; is populated with dozens of videos of himself and his pack goats, Rooster and Peanut, pounding trails all over the west, working the world on &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/span&gt; and CW with just a simple, portable setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, this appealed to me. To me, this is very much in the spirit of amateur radio: pushing the limits of weight, power, and portability to new extremes, and spawning innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, cute mountain goats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sota.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Summits On The Air&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt;) is a program that formalizes this endeavor, providing a framework for hikers (known as &amp;#8220;activators&amp;#8221;) and those who spot them (the &amp;#8220;chasers&amp;#8221;) to gain points and compete with one another. It&amp;#8217;s all in good fun, and the community appears to be very tightly-knit. Every day is an opportunity for a new activation and a new station to chase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales of &lt;a href=&quot;/waveguide/&quot;&gt;WaveGuide&lt;/a&gt; enabled me to purchase my second HF radio, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yaesu.com/indexVS.cfm?cmd=DisplayProducts&amp;amp;ProdCatID=102&amp;amp;encProdID=8CBB7C4BDBAF40129AD4253A4987523C&quot;&gt;Yaesu FT-857D&lt;/a&gt;. Designed for mobile installations in cars, the 857 is very compact and feature-rich, and it even includes &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VHF&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UHF&lt;/span&gt; bands. It&amp;#8217;s a perfect rig for hiking and portable operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Activation Time!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unseasonably-warm weather this March led to my first &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; activation this weekend. My girlfriend, Jess, was kind enough to join me, helping to carry some of the gear. We chose Bare Mountain, in the Holyoke range, because we knew the parking area would be open, and it s a relatively short, albeit steep, hike. After summiting around noon and spending 45 minutes getting the stupid 20m dipole tangled in trees, I was ready to get on the air. There was only one problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The microphone was back at the apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been messing around with digital modes the night before and testing some microphone connections to the PC, and had forgotten to reconnect the mic when I was done. So, it was back down the trail I went. It only took about an hour to hike down, drive home, retrieve, the mic, then drive back and hoof it back to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2:30 PM &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/span&gt; (1830 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UTC&lt;/span&gt;), I was set to go. Over the next hour, the QSOs came in waves, with many &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; spotters reporting in. Signal reports varied from a barely-copyable 44 to booming 59&amp;#8217;s. The band was very fickle, with lots of signal fading occurring over the course of a conversation. I even encountered some intentional &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;QRM&lt;/span&gt; in another language (slurred), but I just ignored it and moved to another frequency. It was annoying, but nothing to lose my cool over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very first &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; activation resulted in 13 QSOs on the 20 meter band, all of them &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/span&gt; mode on just 5W of transmit power. This included DX stations in five other European countries, and five U.S. states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 meter simplex on 146.52 was surprisingly quiet, and I didn&amp;#8217;t make any contacts on &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VHF&lt;/span&gt;. I guess everybody was outside enjoying the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am extremely happy with how everything went. As far as radio conditions go, I could not have asked for more. I met some really great people on the air and made some cool connections within the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; community as a result of the above video, which I think came out really well. I already have another activation planned for next weekend, and I can&amp;#8217;t wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to WG0AT for the fun videos and the inspiration to get involved in &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt;. Thank you to all the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/span&gt; chasers who gave me awesome QSOs this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thank you, Jess, for still dating me after this whole ordeal. I still think you&amp;#8217;re cuter than Rooster and Peanut.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>